The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit
从数百个麻省理工学院的课程中访问
MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw.mit.edu
麻省理工学院的开放式课件网站ocw.mit.edu
PROFESSOR: How about I propose this?
教授：我怎么建议这个？
We go through knapsack because it's
我们经历背包，因为它
on the Pset, not knapsack but a variation of it.
在Pset上，不是背包，而是它的一种变体。
If we have time, we do a couple variations.
如果有时间，我们会做一些变化。
If not, maybe not.
如果不是，也许不是。
And if we have time, we do at a distance.
如果我们有时间，我们可以远距离进行。
Let's see what happens after knapsack.
让我们看看背包之后发生了什么。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: How many people got the difference
教授：有多少人有所作为
between polynomial and pseudo polynomial?
在多项式和伪多项式之间？
OK, so we should definitely do knapsack.
好，所以我们绝对应该做背包。
AUDIENCE: Constant factors, they don't matter.
听众：恒定因素，无所谓。
Oh wait. [INAUDIBLE].
等一下。 [听不清]。
Yeah, they do.
是的，他们有。
PROFESSOR: So the thing is it's not constant factors.
教授：因此，这不是恒定的因素。
That s there is not a constant.
那是没有常数的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So the knapsack problem.
教授：这是背包问题。
So the way I look at it.
所以我看的方式。
You're a thief.
你是小偷
You somehow made your way into a vault.
您以某种方式进入了保险库。
That vault has n items.
那个金库有n个物品。
AUDIENCE: Way better than camping.
听众：比露营更好。
PROFESSOR: Each item has a weight of si pounds,
教授：每件物品的重量为si磅，
and after you get out of the vault,
在您跳出保险库之后，
assuming you make it alive and everything,
假设你活着的一切，
you can sell it for vi dollars on the market,
您可以在市场上以美元出售它，
so this is how much money you get out of it, vi.
因此，这是您从中得到多少钱，vi。
Well, now the problem is the only thing you have with you
好吧，现在的问题是唯一的问题
as you enter that vault is one knapsack that
当您输入Vault是一个背包时，
can carry at most s pounds.
最多可以携带英镑。
If you try to put more stuff in it,
如果您尝试放入更多东西，
so if you try to load it up with more than s pounds,
因此，如果您尝试用超过s磅的重量加载它，
it's going to break as you try to escape from the vault
当您尝试从金库中逃脱时，它会破裂
and stuff is going to fall on the floor,
东西会掉在地上，
and then many laser beams will shred you to pieces,
然后很多激光束会将您切成碎片，
so that's undesirable.
所以这是不可取的。
So we can only load the knapsack with s pounds.
因此，我们只能在背包中装入s磅。
Now, given this restriction, we want
现在，鉴于此限制，我们想要
to make as much money as possible
尽可能赚钱
out of the whole thing, so we want
整个事情，所以我们想要
to load up the knapsack optimally.
以最佳地装载背包。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
Everyone remembers?
每个人都记得吗？
Good.
好。
So two ways to solve it, graphs and dynamic programming.
因此，有两种解决方法，即图形和动态编程。
We're going to do both.
我们将同时做这两个。
Who wants to go for graphs first?
谁想先去看图？
Who wants-- OK, never mind.
谁想要-好吧，没关系。
Majority has been achieved.
已实现多数。
How do we represent this?
我们如何代表这个？
First off, let's represent the solution.
首先，让我们代表解决方案。
Our solution is which items we chose, right?
我们的解决方案是选择哪些项目，对吗？
So we can phrase this as n decisions.
因此，我们可以将其表述为n个决策。
Each decision is a true/false decision,
每个决定都是对/错的决定，
and it indicates if you take that item with you or not.
它指示您是否随身携带该物品。
So di says, do I take item i?
迪说，我拿物品我吗？
So now this looks more like a game.
所以现在看起来更像是一个游戏。
You are on a TV, there's a game show,
您在电视上，有一场游戏节目，
and you get asked n questions.
然后你被问到n个问题。
Do you want to take this item with you, yes or no?
您是否要随身携带这个物品？
If you somehow manage to get items
如果您设法获得物品
that are more than s pounds heavy, you get shot,
超过一磅的重量，您会被枪击，
you don't make it to the end of the game.
您不会一直到游戏结束。
Otherwise, when you leave the game,
否则，当您离开游戏时，
you make some money and the money
你赚一些钱
that you make depends on what items you took with you.
您制作的物品取决于随身携带的物品。
So now this looks like the game problems
所以现在看起来像是游戏问题
that we used to solve with graphs in that you have
我们以前用图来解决
decisions, those decisions are moves,
决定，这些决定就是行动，
and they get you through a graph of states.
他们使您了解状态图。
Now, let's see what's in the state.
现在，让我们看看状态如何。
What do we need to keep track of?
我们需要跟踪什么？
First, we need to keep track of what item we're thinking about,
首先，我们需要跟踪我们正在考虑的项目，
right?
对？
And then there's something else that we need to keep track of.
然后还有其他需要我们跟踪的地方。
AUDIENCE: How much capacity we have.
观众：我们有多少容量。
PROFESSOR: Yep, very good.
教授：是的，很好。
So the reason I need that is when
所以我需要的原因是
I'm deciding whether I'm taking an item or not,
我正在决定是否要拿东西，
I want to know if I'm going to get shot or not.
我想知道我是否会被枪杀。
If I take too much stuff, I'm not going to make it,
如果我吃太多东西，我就不会做，
so I need to know if this item fits in my backpack or not.
所以我需要知道这个东西是否适合我的背包。
That's equivalent to knowing how much weight I have left.
这相当于知道我还剩下多少重量。
So s pounds.
这么磅。
Let's say this is capacity, how much weight
假设这是容量，多少重量
left in my backpack's capacity.
留在我背包里
This is equivalent to how much weight I have accumulated,
这等于我累积了多少重量，
the total weight of my items.
我的物品的总重量。
Weight of the items I have taken so far.
到目前为止，我已拿走的物品的重量。
So the sum of the weights of the taken items.
因此，所取物品的权重之和。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] left.
观众：[听不清]。
Isn't it the total minus?
是总负吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, I'm saying they're equivalent,
教授：好吧，我是说它们是等效的，
so if you know one, you can compute the other.
因此，如果您知道一个，就可以计算另一个。
They're not equal.
他们不平等。
Knowing one lets you know the other one,
知道一个让您知道另一个，
but this is more useful in terms of putting the graph together,
但这对于将图形放在一起更有用，
I claim.
我要求。
We'll see if that is true or not as we
我们将看看这是否正确，因为
try to put the graph together.
尝试将图形放在一起。
So what's a node?
那么什么是节点？
What's an edge?
有什么优势？
AUDIENCE: An edge is putting in one more item,
听众：一项优势正在增加一项，
and a node is a state.
节点就是状态
PROFESSOR: So what the weight going to be on an edge?
教授：那么权重将是什么呢？
If the edge means I'm taking an item,
如果边缘表示我要拿东西，
then the weight is going to be what?
那么重量将是什么？
AUDIENCE: The weight of the item you're adding.
观众：您要添加的商品的重量。
AUDIENCE: The earning associated with that.
听众：与之相关的收入。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
I like this better because in the end,
我更喜欢这个，因为最后
my goal is to maximize earnings, right?
我的目标是使收入最大化，对吗？
And I'm going to feed my graph to a shortest path algorithm.
我将把我的图形输入最短路径算法。
Maximize earnings, minimize path weight.
最大化收益，最小化路径权重。
They're the same issue, flip sign.
他们是同样的问题，翻转迹象。
So I'm going to say this is the value of the item almost.
所以我要说的是这几乎是物品的价值。
Does this work or not?
这行得通吗？
Negative value of the item.
物品的负值。
I have to flip the sign to turn it from a maximization problem
我必须翻转符号以使其摆脱最大化问题
to a minimization problem.
最小化问题。
So shortest path will give me the shortest path.
所以最短的路径会给我最短的路径。
That's going to correspond to making the least
这将相当于使最少
amount of money if I don't add this minus sign.
如果我不加这个减号的话
So what's a node?
那么什么是节点？
AUDIENCE: Is it a unique set of items?
听众：这是一套独特的物品吗？
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: A unique set of items.
听众：一组独特的物品。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So the state in a node is going to have
因此，节点中的状态将具有
i, which is the item that I'm looking at, because this way,
我，这是我正在查看的项目，因为这样，
I'm going to have one node for each item.
我将为每个项目有一个节点。
And what else did I say I need to keep track of?
我还说我还需要跟踪什么？
AUDIENCE: The weight of the taken items.
听众：所取物品的重量。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Weight of taken.
服用重量。
So this is sort of like the gas problem
所以这有点像煤气问题
where you have to keep track of how much gas you have
您必须在哪里跟踪有多少汽油
as well as where you are on the map.
以及您在地图上的位置。
Sorry if it brings bad memories.
对不起，如果它带来不好的回忆。
Let's talk about an example so that we can draw a graph for it
让我们谈一个例子，以便我们可以为其绘制图形
and see what things look like.
看看是什么样子
So say we have three items, and say our backpack
所以说我们有三个项目，然后说我们的背包
has five pounds.
有五磅。
And my three items are a golden statue,
我的三个物品是金色雕像
value $10, weight, four pounds.
价值$ 10，重量，四磅。
These are 1800 dollars when money actually
这些钱实际是1800美元
used to be worth something.
曾经是值得的。
Crystal ball, you can sell this for $4,
水晶球，您可以以4美元的价格将其出售，
and it weighs two pounds, and someone in the previous section
它重两磅，上一节中有人
wanted a fountain pen, so we're going
需要一支钢笔，所以我们要去
to use a fountain pen that's worth $7.
使用价值7美元的钢笔。
Culture is worth a lot of money, right?
文化值得很多钱，对不对？
And weighs three pounds.
并重三磅。
Really ancient fountain pen.
真正古老的钢笔。
I don't know how people wrote with it.
我不知道人们是怎么写的。
So how do we draw the graph for this?
那么我们如何为此绘制图形呢？
AUDIENCE: We'd make a tree where each level the tree
听众：我们会制作一棵树，每层树
is take item i, or don't take item i.
是接受项目i，还是不接受项目i。
Make a big binary tree.
制作一棵大二叉树。
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
PROFESSOR: So if each level of the tree
教授：因此，如果树的每个级别
says whether I'm taking an item or not,
说我是否要带东西，
and then I have two descendants, then that's
然后我有两个后代，那就是
going to be 2 to the number of items.
数量将变为2。
So that's going to be exponential
所以这将是指数
in the number of items, whereas we're
在项目数量上，而我们
going to end up in a solution where the running time is
最终将成为运行时间为
proportional to the number of items.
与项目数量成正比。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: I mean, it makes sense in some cases,
教授：我的意思是，在某些情况下，
if you have fractional costs or something.
如果您有小额费用或其他费用。
By the way, all these weights are integers.
顺便说一下，所有这些权重都是整数。
Sorry I didn't mention that.
抱歉，我没有提到。
My bad.
我的错。
But I like the idea of having some sort of levels based
但是我喜欢基于某种程度的关卡
on items, so let's say I'm going to have a starting node,
在项目上，所以假设我要有一个起始节点，
and then I'm going to have some sort of layer for item one,
然后我将为项目1设置某种层，
some sort of layer for item two, and some sort of layer
项目二的某种层，以及某种层
for item three, some sort of vertical layer.
对于第三项，某种垂直层。
How many nodes do I have in a layer?
一层中有几个节点？
One node for each possible weight
每个可能的权重一个节点
because I promised that in a node, I keep track of the item
因为我答应在一个节点中跟踪该项目
that I'm considering and the weight of the items I've
我正在考虑的东西以及我已经放置的物品的重量
taken so far.
到目前为止。
How many possible weights do I have here?
我在这里有多少个砝码？
AUDIENCE: Three weights.
听众：三重。
PROFESSOR: So my backpack holds five pounds, so what
教授：所以我的背包重五磅，所以
are the possible sums I can get?
我可以得到的可能金额是多少？
How many?
多少？
AUDIENCE: 4, 2, 3, 5.
观众：4、2、3、5。
PROFESSOR: So far, I heard 2 3, 4, 5, 6.
教授：到目前为止，我听到了2 3、4、5、6。
Who wants to bid more?
谁想出价更高？
AUDIENCE: Not more than 6.
听众：不超过6。
PROFESSOR: So the answer is 6, right?
教授：答案是6，对吗？
The possible weights are from 0, which is an empty knapsack,
可能的权重从0开始，这是一个空背包，
until weight 5, which is a full knapsack.
直到重量5，这是一个完整的背包。
So weight 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and I'm
所以体重0、1、2、3、4、5、6，我
going to start drawing the nodes.
开始绘制节点。
AUDIENCE: You could have weight 10.
听众：您的体重可能为10。
PROFESSOR: We're never going to fill up
教授：我们永远不会填补
a knapsack with more than 5.
一个背包超过5个。
Otherwise, we're going to die.
否则，我们就要死了。
AUDIENCE: Why do we have 6, then?
听众：那么为什么我们有6个？
PROFESSOR: Because I can't thank.
教授：因为我不能谢谢。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So this node, the first node.
所以这个节点，第一个节点。
Weight in the backpack, 0.
背包重量为0。
We're looking at item one.
我们正在寻找第一项。
It's connected to the starting node.
它已连接到起始节点。
What outgoing edges do I have?
我有哪些外向边缘？
What do I do with item one?
我如何处理第一个项目？
I can take it or not take it.
我可以接受还是不接受。
AUDIENCE: You connect the edges 4, 2, 3.
听众：连接边缘4、2、3。
Am I answering a different question?
我在回答另一个问题吗？
AUDIENCE: If it's item one, shouldn't it have a weight?
观众：如果是第一项，它不应该有重量吗？
PROFESSOR: So those have two numbers in them, i and j.
教授：所以它们中有两个数字，即i和j。
Sorry.
抱歉。
They're in the wrong order here.
他们在这里的顺序错误。
1, 0.
1，0。
So I'm looking at item one.
所以我在看第一个项目。
So far, I have zero pounds in my backpack.
到目前为止，我的背包中的重量为零。
Looking at item two with zero pounds, looking at item three
看着零磅的第二项，看着第三项
with zero pounds.
零磅。
Looking at item one with one pound in my backpack,
看着背包里有一磅的物品一，
item two with one pound, item three with one pound,
第2项重1磅，第3项重1磅，
so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So if I'm looking at item one, and I
所以，如果我正在看第一个项目，我
have zero pounds in my backpack so far, what happens if I don't
到目前为止，背包中的重量为零磅，如果我没有，该怎么办
take item one?
拿第一项？
Where do I end up?
我到哪里去？
AUDIENCE: 2, 0.
观众：2、0。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So I'm looking at item two after I'm done deciding,
所以我决定后要看第二项，
what do I do with item one, and if I don't take item one,
我该如何处理第一项，如果我不参加第一项，
then I'm not going to have anything in my backpack.
那我的背包里什么都不会了。
So this edge corresponds to we don't just take one.
因此，这一优势对应于我们不只是采取一个。
What if I want to take item one?
如果我想参加第一项怎么办？
Where do I land?
我在哪里着陆？
AUDIENCE: 2, 4.
观众：2、4。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
2, 3.
2、3
2, 4.
2、4
So if I did take item one, then I
因此，如果我确实接受了第一项，那么我
had zero pounds in my backpack before.
以前我的背包零磅
Now I have four pounds, and I'm still considering item two.
现在我有4磅，而我仍在考虑第二项。
What about edge weights?
边缘权重呢？
What's the weight of the edge that
边缘的重量是多少
says I don't take item one?
说我不服用第一项？
What's the weight of the edge that says I do take item one?
说我要拿第一件东西的边缘的重量是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: Minus 10.
听众：减10。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
0 and minus 10.
0到10。
That minus lets us get the shortest path.
减号使我们得到最短的路径。
Now, suppose I'm in 2, 0.
现在，假设我处于2、0。
What are the outgoing edges?
什么是传出边缘？
AUDIENCE: It's the same as making a giant binary tree,
听众：就像制作一棵巨大的二叉树一样，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: It's not going to be a tree because I
教授：那不是一棵树，因为我
can have multiple paths from a root to some node.
从根到某个节点可以有多个路径。
AUDIENCE: But this looks like it's taking the same complexity
听众：但这看起来就像是复杂的事情
as building a tree if you were to carefully build the tree so
就像建造一棵树，如果您要仔细地建造树，
that you don't have unfeasible solutions on the tree.
您在树上没有不可行的解决方案。
PROFESSOR: Then you're actually doing dynamic programming.
教授：那么您实际上是在进行动态编程。
You're not building the tree if you're doing that.
如果这样做，您就没有在构建树。
You're still converging to this.
您仍在收敛。
You're probably thinking this and you said binary
你可能在想这个，你说二进制
decision tree, or at least that's what I understood.
决策树，或者至少这就是我的理解。
You're probably thinking of the right thing.
您可能正在考虑正确的事情。
We can see if we're thinking the same thing when we end up
结束时我们可以看看是否在想同样的事情
looking at the running time.
看运行时间。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: The goal here is to have the most valuable items
观众：这里的目标是拥有最有价值的物品
possible in the bag in terms of money?
可能在钱袋上？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
PROFESSOR: So the negative 10 weight
教授：那么负10权重
that you have there was because that item was $10.
那是因为该物品价值10美元。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And in the end, we're going to give the graph to the shortest
最后，我们将使图形最短
path algorithm.
路径算法。
So yes, speaking of the goal, what's the answer here,
是的，谈到目标，这里的答案是什么，
by the way?
顺便说说？
AUDIENCE: 11.
听众：11。
PROFESSOR: 11.
教授：11。
How do I get 11?
我如何获得11？
AUDIENCE: By getting the last two items.
听众：获得最后两项。
PROFESSOR: So I take the ball and the pen
教授：所以我拿球和笔
and I get 11, right?
我得到11，对吗？
Everyone on the same page?
每个人都在同一页面上吗？
So I'm at item two.
所以我在第二项。
I have zero pounds in my backpack.
我的背包零磅。
What are my outgoing edges?
我的外向优势是什么？
AUDIENCE: To 3, 0 and to 3, 2.
听众：分别为3，0和3，2。
Wait, sorry.
等一下对不起
That's the third item.
那是第三项。
PROFESSOR: No, second item.
教授：不，第二项。
You're good.
你很厉害。
AUDIENCE: Shouldn't it be 3, 3 because the third item
听众：不应该是3、3，因为第三项
has three pounds?
有三磅？
PROFESSOR: I said I'm looking at the second item
教授：我说我正在看第二项
and then I'm deciding where I'm going.
然后我决定要去哪里。
So this graph has a problem in that
所以这个图有一个问题
when I get to the third item, what do I do?
当我转到第三项时，该怎么办？
So I need one more layer here, which means that I'm done.
因此，我在这里还需要一层，这意味着我已经完成。
AUDIENCE: I was saying that it's the outgoing edge from 2, 0,
听众：我是说这是2、0的输出边缘，
it's the weight of the taken item,
这是所取物品的重量，
so if you decide to take the third item,
因此，如果您决定采取第三项，
shouldn't the outgoing edge go to 3, 3, not 3, 2?
传出的边不应该转到3、3，而不是3、2吗？
PROFESSOR: But when I'm at layer two,
教授：但是当我在第二层时，
I'm only looking at item two.
我只看第二项。
So I'm looking at the items in sequence.
因此，我按顺序查看这些项目。
First I have to decide, am I taking item one?
首先，我必须决定，我要服用第一个吗？
Then I decide, am I taking item two, and then I'm deciding,
然后我决定，我是否要考虑第二项，然后我决定
am I taking item three?
我要服用第三项吗？
While I'm here, I don't see item three.
我在这里的时候，我没有看到第三项。
I only see item two.
我只看到第二项。
AUDIENCE: Aren't those weights on the left side, though?
听众：那些重量不是在左侧吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
These are backpack weights.
这些是背包的重量。
So down here, these are pounds and these are items.
所以在这里，这些是磅，这些是物品。
What are the weights on the edges?
边缘的重量是多少？
0 and negative 1.
0和负1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
How about this other node, 2, 4?
这个另一个节点2、4呢？
What are the edges coming out of it.
有什么优势呢？
AUDIENCE: 2, 0.
观众：2、0。
AUDIENCE: 3, 4.
观众：3、4。
PROFESSOR: So if I decide I'm not going to take item two,
教授：所以，如果我决定不参加第二项，
but I already have four pounds in my backpack,
但是我的背包已经有四磅了
I'm still going to end up with four pounds in my backpack,
我仍然要背着四磅的背包，
and I don't get anything out of it.
而且我什么都没有。
And?
和？
AUDIENCE: That's it.
听众：就是这样。
PROFESSOR: And that's it, because if I
教授：就这样，因为如果我
try to take the second item, that would put me overweight,
尝试第二项，那会让我超重，
so the edge would go out of the graph.
因此边缘将超出图表。
Therefore, it doesn't exist.
因此，它不存在。
AUDIENCE: You can remove it, and then you go back to 3, 0,
听众：您可以将其删除，然后返回到3，0，
right?
对？
Is that not allowed?
那是不允许的吗？
PROFESSOR: No, because when I'm here,
教授：不，因为当我在这里时，
I don't know how I got here.
我不知道怎么到这里。
I don't know if I had item one or not.
我不知道我是否有第一项。
The benefits of doing it this way is here,
这样做的好处就在这里，
I'm just looking at item two.
我只是在看第二项。
I do not know how I got there.
我不知道我怎么到那里。
I do not care what I'm going to do later.
我不在乎以后要做什么。
I'm just looking at one item and making
我只是看一件东西而已
one decision based on that.
一个基于此的决定。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
Where do I get my answer from?
我从哪里得到答案？
AUDIENCE: Can you put a final node on the right side?
听众：您可以在右侧放置最后一个节点吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, so one way of doing
教授：好的，所以一种方法
it is that I'm going to have a final note on the right side
我要在右边有最后的音符
and connecting everything to it.
并连接所有内容。
AUDIENCE: Do you need the done nodes right there,
听众：您是否需要在那里完成的节点，
or could you have just skipped done and connected 3 to that?
还是您可以跳过完成并连接3到那个？
PROFESSOR: So I can do that, but then it's
教授：所以我可以做到，但是后来
going to be hard to reason about edges.
很难推理边缘。
This makes it easier to reason about edges
这使得更容易推理边缘
because when I'm looking at this layer,
因为当我看着这一层时
I'm still going to have edges deciding
我仍然会决定
whether I take item three or not.
无论我是否服用第三项。
So it would be confusing to have all the edges pointing
所以让所有的边都指向会令人困惑
to the same place.
到同一个地方。
I can, it's just that the graph would look more confusing.
我可以，只是该图看起来更加混乱。
By the way, if I'm at 3, 2, what are the outgoing edges
顺便说一句，如果我在3、2，传出的边是什么
from 3, 2?
从3，2？
AUDIENCE: It's just all horizontal.
听众：都是水平的。
You can't take anymore.
你不能再忍受了。
PROFESSOR: So I can be done with two pounds,
教授：所以我可以吃两磅，
and that means I get 0 or I can take
这意味着我得到0或我可以接受
item three, and then where do I land?
第三项，然后我在哪里着陆？
AUDIENCE: Negative 7.
听众：负面7。
PROFESSOR: Does this make sense now somewhat?
教授：这现在有些道理吗？
AUDIENCE: So what about this dynamic programming style?
听众：那么这种动态编程风格呢？
PROFESSOR: We'll get there in a bit.
教授：我们待会儿到达。
Before, let's see what's the running time for this.
之前，让我们看看它的运行时间是多少。
So one way of finishing this up is
因此，完成此操作的一种方法是
we connect everything to one destination node.
我们将所有内容都连接到一个目标节点。
Another way of doing it is that we connect the source nodes
另一种方法是我们连接源节点
to everything here with edges of cost 0 and say,
对这里所有成本为0的东西说：
well, this is how much weight we're going to waste.
好吧，这就是我们要浪费的重量。
So if my solution path goes here and then goes
所以，如果我的解决方案走到这里然后走
somewhere through the graph, it means
在图表的某处，这意味着
that I'm going to waste one pound of capacity,
我要浪费一磅的容量，
so my backpack is going to have four pounds when I'm done.
所以当我做完后，我的背包要重四磅。
AUDIENCE: Would it be [INAUDIBLE] or infinity?
听众：是[听不清]还是无限？
PROFESSOR: What should the weight be?
教授：体重应该是多少？
Good question.
好问题。
AUDIENCE: This is not possible, right?
听众：这是不可能的，对吗？
To get from s to 1, 1.
从s到1，1。
PROFESSOR: So I'm saying that if I get from s to 1, 1,
教授：所以我说的是，如果我从s到1，
this means that I'm wasting a pound.
这意味着我在浪费磅。
My backpack will have four pounds of stuff
我的背包里有四磅的东西
and then one pound of capacity will go to waste.
那么一磅的容量将被浪费。
AUDIENCE: Isn't there another way
听众：没有别的办法了
to waste it on the right side if you end at the top?
如果您在顶部结束，则将其浪费在右侧？
Or not at the bottom, basically.
基本上还是不在底部。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So you're not double counting
听众：所以您不会重复计算
in terms of losing stuff?
在失去东西方面？
You're representing losing weight
你代表减肥
on the left side and the right side.
在左侧和右侧。
PROFESSOR: Well, if I represent losing weight on the left side,
教授：好吧，如果我代表左侧减肥，
then the advantage is that I have a single destination node.
那么好处是我只有一个目标节点。
What is it?
它是什么？
AUDIENCE: That dot.
听众：那个点。
PROFESSOR: So this is the source.
教授：这就是来源。
The destination is this guy.
目的地是这个家伙。
I can waste capacity here, so that
我可以在这里浪费容量，这样
means I can say that on this side,
意思是我可以这样说
I don't need to waste stuff.
我不需要浪费东西。
On this side, I need to arrive at done 5.
在这一方面，我需要完成5。
That's the advantage of doing it this way, aside from the fact
这是这样做的好处，除了事实
that it's going to map to dynamic programming.
它将映射到动态编程。
There are many ways of doing it.
有很多方法可以做到这一点。
I can choose to connect the source to 1, 0,
我可以选择将源连接到1、0，
and then look at all the paths here and choose the best one.
然后在这里查看所有路径并选择最佳路径。
I can connect the source to everything
我可以将源连接到一切
here with paths of some weight, which you guys still
这里有一些重量的路径，你们仍然
need to tell me what it is, and then I can look at the answer
需要告诉我它是什么，然后我可以看看答案
here.
这里。
AUDIENCE: Cost 0.
观众：费用0。
PROFESSOR: Thank you.
教授：谢谢。
So this is another way.
所以这是另一种方式。
And yet the third way would be to only connect
但是第三种方式是只连接
the source to the first node, and then
源到第一个节点，然后
connect all these done nodes to another node with cost 0,
将所有这些完成的节点连接到成本为0的另一个节点，
and this is equivalent to this.
这等效于此。
The reason we're doing it this way
我们这样做的原因
is because this maps to dynamic programming.
是因为这映射到动态编程。
AUDIENCE: Easier.
听众：更容易。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
It maps closely to how the DP runs.
它与DP的运行方式密切相关。
AUDIENCE: I mean is it possible to do the DP such
听众：我的意思是可以这样做DP
that you do it the other way as well?
你也用其他方式做？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
You can flip the DP around, too.
您也可以翻转DP。
How are we doing with this?
我们如何处理呢？
So then I hope the running time analysis will go really fast.
因此，我希望运行时间分析能很快进行。
How many vertices?
多少个顶点？
AUDIENCE: v or three.
听众：v或3。
PROFESSOR: OK, so v is?
教授：好的，v是吗？
AUDIENCE: ns.
听众：ns。
PROFESSOR: n layers, right?
教授：n层吧？
n plus 1 layers, actually.
n加1层，实际上。
AUDIENCE: n times weight mass.
听众：质量的n倍。
PROFESSOR: n times capacity, right?
教授：容量是n倍，对吗？
So it's actually n plus 1 times capacity plus 1,
所以实际上是n加1倍的容量再加上1
but I don't want to deal with that,
但我不想处理
so I'm going to use order of so that I
所以我将使用的顺序
don't have to deal with that.
不必处理。
How many edges going out of a vertex?
顶点有多少条边？
AUDIENCE: Two.
听众：两个。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So at most, two edges per vertex.
因此，每个顶点最多两个边缘。
So how many edges total?
那么总共有多少条边？
AUDIENCE: ns.
听众：ns。
PROFESSOR: What shortest path algorithm am I going to use?
教授：我要使用哪种最短路径算法？
AUDIENCE: Bellman-Ford.
听众：贝尔曼·福特。
AUDIENCE: Topological sort BFS.
听众：拓扑排序BFS。
PROFESSOR: I'm going to choose the second one
教授：我要选择第二个
because it runs faster.
因为它运行速度更快。
So Bellman-Ford's running time is V times E.
因此，贝尔曼福特的运行时间是V乘以E。
If I use the DAG algorithm, that means topological sort and then
如果我使用DAG算法，则意味着拓扑排序，然后
a DFS.
DFS。
That's V plus E. So please, whenever
那是V加E。所以请随时
you have a dynamic programming graph, this is the answer.
您有一个动态的编程图，这就是答案。
It's never anything else.
别无其他
It's never Dijkstra.
从来没有Dijkstra。
It's never Bellman-Ford.
从来都不是贝尔曼福特。
It's always this.
总是这样。
And this means?
这是什么意思？
AUDIENCE: ns.
听众：ns。
PROFESSOR: So this is the running time
教授：这是运行时间
of the graph solution.
图解。
AUDIENCE: If you use BFS, do you need
听众：如果您使用BFS，是否需要
to put in the dummy nodes for the edge weights?
放在虚拟节点的边缘权重？
PROFESSOR: If you use BFS.
教授：如果您使用BFS。
Yes.
是。
So then the running time would be bigger than V plus E.
因此，运行时间将大于V加E。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
So then the running time depends on [INAUDIBLE]
因此，运行时间取决于[音频不清晰]
multiply by s again?
再乘以s？
PROFESSOR: This isn't doing BFS.
教授：这不是在做BFS。
This is doing the shortest path algorithm
这是最短路径算法
for direct acyclic graphs.
用于直接非循环图。
It's the DAG shortest path.
这是DAG最短的路径。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: Were you here before Thanksgiving?
教授：感恩节之前您来过这里吗？
AUDIENCE: No
听众：否
PROFESSOR: Right before?
教授：在吗？
You missed the algorithm.
您错过了算法。
It's in the Dijkstra lecture notes.
在Dijkstra的讲义中。
AUDIENCE: But basically, you don't
听众：但是基本上，你不会
have to put in all the dummy nodes?
必须放入所有虚拟节点？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
So you do a topological sort, and then
因此，您进行拓扑排序，然后
you only consider a node once, and you
您只考虑一次节点，然后
look at all the edges coming through it
看看穿过它的所有边缘
and make a decision based on that.
并据此做出决定。
So this is the running time, this is the algorithm,
这是运行时间，这是算法，
this is the solution.
这是解决方案。
What if we do dynamic programming instead?
如果我们改为进行动态编程怎么办？
Instead of nodes, we have sub-problems.
除了子节点，我们还有子问题。
A sub-problem maps to a node.
子问题映射到节点。
The same things that we decided about this data
我们对这些数据做出的决定相同
that we store in a node, the same things
我们存储在节点中的相同内容
are going to apply to the state that we have in a sub-problem.
将适用于子问题中的状态。
So what are the sub-problems?
那么子问题是什么？
First up, how many sub-problems am I going to have?
首先，我将要解决几个子问题？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
AUDIENCE: ns.
听众：ns。
PROFESSOR: I just said that one sub-problem
教授：我只是说一个子问题
will map to a vertex in the graph.
将映射到图中的顶点。
ns vertices, ns sub-problems, right?
ns顶点，ns子问题，对不对？
Come on, guys.
拜托了伙计们。
Bear with me.
忍受我。
Get more cookies.
获取更多Cookie。
Are the cookies still there?
饼干还在吗？
Please pass them around and eat them.
请把它们传给他们吃。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: One sub-problem would be getting the most amount
听众：一个子问题将获得最大的收益
of money for that little weight.
这么小的重量的钱。
At one pound [INAUDIBLE], how much [INAUDIBLE].
一磅[音频不清晰]，多少[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: I like that, so let's start writing.
教授：我喜欢，所以让我们开始写作。
What is the maximum value that I can get using a certain weight?
使用一定重量可以得到的最大值是多少？
If I label the nodes indices i, j, I'm
如果我标记节点索引i，j，我就是
also going to label the sub-problems using i, j.
也将使用i，j标记子问题。
So I'm going to say that sub-problem i, j
所以我要说这个子问题i，j
is, what's the maximum amount of money
是，最大金额是多少
I can get by using a weight of at most j,
我最多可以使用j的权重，
and you said something about items,
你说了一些关于物品的事，
so we have to figure out which items.
所以我们必须找出哪些项目。
Which items?
哪些项目？
Anyone else can help her.
任何人都可以帮助她。
You already did the hard work, so you
您已经做了艰苦的工作，所以您
have most of the stuff filled in.
填满了大多数东西。
Feel free to jump in.
随时加入。
AUDIENCE: Greater than or equal to i.
听众：大于或等于i。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
We're going to number the items starting from 0 this time
这次我们将从0开始编号
because we're going to have a dynamic programming table,
因为我们要有一个动态的编程表，
and that means we like zero base indexing.
这意味着我们喜欢零基索引。
So the items are going to be 0, 1, and 2.
因此项目将分别为0、1和2。
0 is the statue, 1 is the ball, and 2 is the pen.
0是雕像，1是球，2是笔。
This means we're going to look at suffixes of items.
这意味着我们将查看项目的后缀。
First, the empty set, no item, then only
首先是空集，没有项目，然后只有
the pen, then the ball and the pen, and then
笔，然后是球和笔，然后
the statue, the ball, and the pen.
雕像，球和笔。
And we're also going to consider how much weight we
我们还将考虑我们有多重
have in our backpack.
在我们的背包里。
So let me write this again.
所以，让我再写一次。
0, 1, 2 here, and weights 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and this
0、1、2，权重为0、1、2、3、4、5，以及此
is going to be our DP table.
将成为我们的DP表。
Now, how are we going to compute this?
现在，我们将如何计算呢？
DP of i, j is?
i，j的DP是？
AUDIENCE: Maximum.
听众：最高。
PROFESSOR: All right, a maximum of something.
教授：好的，最多。
Good.
好。
Perfect way to start.
完美的开始方式。
How many decisions do we have?
我们有多少个决定？
AUDIENCE: Two.
听众：两个。
PROFESSOR: Two.
教授：两个。
It's the same as in the graph problem, right?
和图问题一样，对吧？
Once we solve that, this should be pretty easy
一旦我们解决了，这应该很容易
because it's really very similar.
因为它非常相似。
So the two decisions are, do I take item i,
所以这两个决定是，我是否接受项目i，
do I not take item i?
我不带物品我吗？
If I don't take item i, what situation do I land in?
如果我不带物品i，我会处于什么情况？
So suppose I don't take item i.
因此，假设我不接受项目i。
AUDIENCE: i plus 1.
听众：我加1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
i plus 1.
我加1。
So I have to make up my answer using items i plus 1
所以我必须用我加1的项目来弥补我的答案
all the way through n minus 1, and how much weight
一直到n减1，到底有多少重量
do they have to have?
他们必须有吗？
AUDIENCE: j.
听众：j。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Now suppose I do take item i.
现在假设我确实接受了项目i。
What happens?
怎么了？
AUDIENCE: i plus-- no, no, no.
听众：我加-不，不，不。
PROFESSOR: You're thinking of the right thing.
教授：您正在思考正确的事情。
We're making some money, right?
我们正在赚钱，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Value i.
听众：值i。
PROFESSOR: Value i.
教授：值i。
So this is how much money we're making.
这就是我们赚多少钱。
Good.
好。
AUDIENCE: Plus dp i plus 1 j minus weight i.
听众：加上dp i加1 j减去重量i。
PROFESSOR: Make sense?
教授：有道理吗？
OK Now I only have to do one more thing to make sure
好，现在我只需要再做一件事来确保
this code doesn't crash.
此代码不会崩溃。
AUDIENCE: I'm sorry.
听众：对不起。
What's the third term for?
第三个名词是什么？
PROFESSOR: This is I'm making some money, right?
教授：这是我在赚钱，对吗？
This means I'm going to have to look at the items
这意味着我将不得不看一下这些物品
starting from i plus 1 and i minus 1.
从我加1开始到我减1。
And now I took item i, so that means
现在我拿了项目i，这意味着
I have si pounds in my backpack.
我的背包里有磅。
So the remaining items must weigh j minus si pounds
因此，其余物品的重量必须为j减去si磅
because I'm going to add the si pounds for this item,
因为我要为此商品加磅
and in total, I'm going to have at most j pounds.
总共，我最多只能有j磅。
Make some money, lose some capacity.
赚一些钱，失去一些能力。
AUDIENCE: Did we [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：我们[听不清]吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
This is what happens when you move from the graph
这是当您从图表移开时发生的情况
to dynamic programming, or you can
进行动态编程，或者您可以
draw the graph the other way around.
反之亦然。
AUDIENCE: So could you have also done plus si,
听众：所以你还可以加上si，
and then done something else as well?
然后再做其他事情？
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
Plus si--
加si--
AUDIENCE: If you did plus si and then you
听众：如果您加了si，那么您
did some other check case that was different.
做了其他一些不同的检查情况。
PROFESSOR: Well, I do need to make a check.
教授：好，我需要检查一下。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
So that's greater than or equal to 0.
因此该值大于或等于0。
PROFESSOR: This thing, right?
教授：这个东西，对吗？
Because otherwise, the code is going to crash.
因为否则，代码将崩溃。
So j minus si is greater or equal to 0.
因此j减去si等于或大于0。
I think this means j is greater than or equal to si, right?
我认为这意味着j大于或等于si，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
At least for me, the natural order when I have the graph
至少对我来说，我有图时的自然顺序
is to consider the moves that by making in the game.
是考虑游戏中的动作。
I'm answering the questions one by one.
我正在一个接一个地回答问题。
Do I take this item?
我要带这个东西吗？
Do I not take this item?
我不带这个东西吗？
When I'm in the DP, when I make a decision,
当我在DP中时，当我做出决定时，
I want to have the full information on that decision.
我想要有关该决定的完整信息。
Whether I take the item or not depends
我是否带物品取决于
on what would happen with the items following it.
接下来的项目将会发生什么。
Representing it this way allows me
用这种方式代表我
to make the decision right here.
在这里做出决定。
AUDIENCE: If we'd done prefixes rather than suffixes,
听众：如果我们要使用前缀而不是后缀，
we could have done it the same.
我们本来可以做到的。
PROFESSOR: It would have been exactly the same as there.
教授：那应该和那里完全一样。
So we taught dynamic programming over many years,
因此，我们教授了很多年的动态编程，
and it turns out that people understand suffixes
事实证明人们理解后缀
better than prefixes, and the graph format
比前缀和图形格式更好
makes more sense that way, so that's
这样更有意义，所以
why we're doing it this way.
为什么我们要这样做
It's for your own sake.
是为了你自己
Trust me.
相信我。
Or at least we think so.
或者至少我们是这样认为的。
AUDIENCE: Where does suffix come in?
听众：后缀在哪里出现？
I know what it means.
我知道那是什么意思
PROFESSOR: These guys.
教授：这些家伙。
These are the sub-problems.
这些是子问题。
Nothing, item two, items one, two, zero, one, two,
一无所有，第二项，第一，二，零，一，二，
so it's a suffix of the set of items.
所以这是项目集的后缀。
AUDIENCE: How come you're going backwards rather than forwards?
听众：你为什么倒退而不是前进？
It doesn't actually matter if you go backwards or forwards?
向前还是向后走都没关系吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
In the end, we're going to look at everything.
最后，我们将研究所有内容。
So we need two things.
所以我们需要两件事。
We need to know where is the answer going to be,
我们需要知道答案在哪里，
and we need to know what are the initial conditions.
我们需要知道初始条件是什么。
Actually, I lied.
其实我说谎
We also need a topological sort.
我们还需要一种拓扑排序。
So where do we want to start?
那么我们要从哪里开始呢？
AUDIENCE: First one.
听众：第一个。
PROFESSOR: Where is the answer?
教授：答案在哪里？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: The lower right hand corner.
听众：右下角。
I mean, if you have all the [INAUDIBLE] nodes.
我的意思是，如果您具有所有的[音频不清晰]节点。
Oh, we don't have a Done column, do we?
哦，我们没有“完成”列，对吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
Well, so the answer will have considered all the items,
好吧，答案将考虑所有项目，
right?
对？
AUDIENCE: Top left.
听众：左上方。
PROFESSOR: So which i?
教授：那我呢？
Almost.
几乎。
So the top left corner means I looked at all the items
因此，左上角表示我查看了所有项目
and I have an empty knapsack.
而且我有一个空的背包。
AUDIENCE: Oh, so the max of all of the first column.
听众：哦，所以第一列的最大值。
PROFESSOR: So the max of all columns
教授：所以所有列的最大值
would be the answer if the weight here would be equal,
如果这里的权重相等，将是答案，
but I said the weight has to be smaller or equal,
但我说权重必须小于或等于
so the answer is easier.
因此答案更容易。
I don't have to do a max.
我不必做最大。
AUDIENCE: Bottom left corner.
听众：左下角。
PROFESSOR: I can only look here.
教授：我只能在这里看看。
So this means that I will use a weight of at most s,
因此，这意味着我将最多使用s的权重，
because this is s, and I will have considered items 0
因为这是s，所以我将考虑项目0
and larger, so all the items.
和更大的，所以所有的项目。
This is where the answer is.
答案就在这里。
And in general terms, that means DP of what and what?
一般而言，这意味着什么以及什么的DP？
So what's the bottom left corner?
那么左下角是什么？
AUDIENCE: 0, s.
听众：0，秒。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Can you explain again why it needs to be DP 0, s.
听众：您能再解释一下为什么它必须是DP 0 s吗？
PROFESSOR: I think it's easier to look at 0,
教授：我认为看0更容易，
s and see how it maps to the sub-problem,
并查看它如何映射到子问题，
and then convince yourself that this is the answer,
然后说服自己这就是答案，
so let's do that.
所以让我们这样做。
DP of 0, s means i is 0, j is s.
DP为0，s表示i为0，j为s。
So this is going to tell me what is
所以这将告诉我什么是
the maximum amount of dollars I can
我可以的最大金额
get by using a weight of at most s-- agrees
通过使用最多s的权重获得-同意
with the initial problem-- and using items i or greater
最初的问题-并使用项目i或更大
than i, or 0 or more, so items 0 through n minus 1.
比i或0或更大，所以项0到n减1。
These are all the items.
这些都是项目。
This is the maximum capacity, so this maps
这是最大容量，因此此图
to the initial problem.
最初的问题。
And that's why I did this.
这就是为什么我这样做。
That's why I don't have an equal sign here.
这就是为什么我在这里没有等号。
AUDIENCE: And if you did have an equal sign,
听众：如果你确实有一个等号，
then you would be changing your sub-problems?
那你会改变你的子问题吗？
PROFESSOR: The recursion stays the same,
教授：递归保持不变，
but I have to look at all these to get the maximum.
但我必须仔细研究所有这些，才能获得最大的收益。
Someone suggested that.
有人建议。
AUDIENCE: If you put an equals there,
听众：如果在那放等号，
you're going to have to do something to the DP such
您将不得不对DP做一些事情，例如
that the equals actually is captivated,
平等实际上被迷住了，
because you can't just arbitrarily--
因为你不能随便-
PROFESSOR: What do you think of this?
教授：您对此有何看法？
AUDIENCE: Something there is going to change, isn't it?
听众：那里会发生变化，不是吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
I think this works.
我认为这可行。
This stays the same no matter what the sign is.
无论符号是什么，都保持不变。
The only thing that changes is where is the answer
唯一改变的是答案在哪里
and what are the initial conditions.
初始条件是什么
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
So there's something else that changes.
因此，还有其他变化。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Initial conditions.
初始条件。
Good.
好。
I like that you're thinking about that
我喜欢你在想那个
because the next problem changes pretty much that.
因为下一个问题几乎改变了这一点。
The sign changes and then these change.
符号改变，然后这些改变。
What's a good topological sort?
什么是好的拓扑？
This should be pretty easy.
这应该很容易。
If I want to generate a topological sort,
如果要生成拓扑排序，
what variables do I iterate over, and in what order?
我要遍历哪些变量，顺序是什么？
AUDIENCE: i.
听众：i。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And you're pointing at n, right?
你指的是n，对吗？
AUDIENCE: n down to 0.
听众：n降至0。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And then the only one left is j, so i in, and then j
然后剩下的唯一一个是j，所以我进入，然后是j
goes from where to where?
从哪里到哪里？
AUDIENCE: j goes to s.
听众：j转到s。
AUDIENCE: It can go either direction.
听众：它可以向任何方向发展。
PROFESSOR: Can it?
教授：可以吗？
What do the dependencies look like?
依赖性是什么样的？
When I'm computing i, j, I want i plus 1 and j minus--
当我计算i，j时，我希望我加1且j减去-
so I'm looking at lower j's, higher i's and lower j's.
所以我在看低j，高i和低j。
AUDIENCE: But it's always higher i's.
听众：但是我总是更高。
Doesn't that mean in this for loop
那不是在这个for循环中
that you're already going to have calculated the next right
您已经要计算出下一个权利
column, so it doesn't matter where
列，所以在哪里都没有关系
the column-- I may be wrong.
专栏-我可能是错的。
PROFESSOR: You're right.
教授：对。
Fine.
精细。
OK, both orders work.
好，两个订单都可以。
I just looked at this because I wanted
我只是看着这个，因为我想要
to have a nice, simple-- but fine, both work.
拥有一个很好，简单但很好的方法，两者都可以工作。
AUDIENCE: Wait.
听众：等等。
You mean reversing j works?
你的意思是逆转j作品？
PROFESSOR: Yes, because we're iterating over i
教授：是的，因为我们正在迭代我
before iterating over j.
在迭代j之前。
Of course, this makes more sense.
当然，这更有意义。
Just because they're both good answers
只是因为他们都是好答案
doesn't mean you should choose the one that
并不意味着您应该选择一个
requires more thinking.
需要更多的思考。
I always like the answer that requires the least
我总是喜欢要求最少的答案
amount of thinking to prove that it's correct.
大量的想法证明它是正确的。
AUDIENCE: Does that mean you're starting with a full--
听众：这是否意味着您是从完整的-
PROFESSOR: I start here.
教授：我从这里开始。
AUDIENCE: But if you're going from s down to 0,
观众：但是如果您要从s降到0，
then you're starting down at the corner, which
然后你从拐角处开始
means you have a full knapsack, so that doesn't make sense.
意味着您有一个完整的背包，所以这没有任何意义。
PROFESSOR: So the argument was when I compute this,
教授：所以争论是当我计算这个的时候，
I'm looking one right, i plus 1j,
我向右看，我加上1j，
and then I'm looking somewhere here.
然后我正在这里找地方。
And I've already computed this column,
我已经计算了此列，
so it doesn't matter if I go up or down.
所以无论我上升还是下降都没关系。
And that argument is correct because first I'm
这种说法是正确的，因为首先我是
going to compute this column, then this column, then
要计算此列，然后计算此列，然后
this column, then this column.
此列，然后是此列。
By the way, what's this column?
顺便问一下，这个专栏是什么？
This column is the initial condition.
此列是初始条件。
Now that we figured out the topological sort,
现在我们已经弄清楚了拓扑排序，
let's try to compute values here and see
让我们尝试在此处计算值并查看
what the initial condition should be.
初始条件应该是什么。
So if I want to compute DP of 2, 0,
因此，如果我想计算2、0的DP，
that is the maximum of either DP 3, 0 or something else.
这是DP 3、0或其他最大值。
This is going to evaluate to false,
这将评估为false，
so it's going to be this.
所以将是这样。
What should the answer be here?
答案应该是什么？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: 0.
教授：0。
So we want DP of 3, 0 to be 0 for this to work.
因此，我们希望3的DP为0才能起作用。
So what's a reasonable initial condition?
那么合理的初始条件是什么？
AUDIENCE: Column 3 is of 0 height.
观众：第3栏的高度为0。
PROFESSOR: DP of nj is 0 for all j,
教授：对于所有j，nj的DP为0，
pretty much what you said in math mode.
几乎是您在数学模式下所说的
So I'm going to have an extra column.
因此，我将增加一列。
This is like the Done problem over there,
就像那边的“完成”问题，
and here I'm going to say that whenever
在这里我要说的是
I'm looking at the empty subset--
我正在看空的子集-
these are all suffixes.
这些都是后缀。
All three items, two items, one item, empty suffix.
所有三个项目，两个项目，一个项目，后缀为空。
Whenever I look at the empty suffix,
每当我看空的后缀时
I can fill up a backpack with any weight by using no items,
我不用任何物品就可以装满任何重量的背包，
and I'm going to make 0 money.
我要赚0钱。
So what are the values here?
那么，这里的值是多少？
You guys nodded, so you understood,
你们点点头，所以您明白了，
so then you should be able to dictate
所以你应该能够决定
the values in the table.
表中的值。
AUDIENCE: So is that one also 0 because you can't go up
观众：那也是0，因为你不能上
to anything, and then the next one is 4 because you can go--
到任何东西，然后下一个是4，因为您可以
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
Next one is-- so it's for the fountain pen, right?
下一个是-就是钢笔吧？
Last item.
最后一项。
AUDIENCE: Crystal ball.
听众：水晶球。
PROFESSOR: So we're going statute, ball, pen.
教授：所以我们要制定法规，球，笔。
AUDIENCE: And this is weight on the left side, right?
听众：这是左边的重量，对吗？
PROFESSOR: So we're filling them like this
教授：所以我们正在这样填补他们
in the topological sort order that we chose here.
按照我们在此处选择的拓扑排序顺序。
We said this is the order, so this
我们说这是命令，所以这
is what we're going to use to calculate the table.
这就是我们将要用来计算表格的内容。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
So it's still 0, then.
因此，它仍然为0。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: 7.
听众：7。
PROFESSOR: So here, this condition
教授：所以这里
is going to evaluate to True finally,
最终将评估为True，
so this is going to be the maximum of either DP i plus 1j,
因此这将是DP i加1j的最大值，
so DP of 3, 3, which is 0, or 7 plus DP of 3, 0.
因此DP为3、3（即0）或7加上DP为3、0。
So 7 plus 0, which is 7.
因此7加0，即7。
That's why it's 7.
这就是为什么它是7。
AUDIENCE: 7, 7.
听众：7，7。
PROFESSOR: 7, 7.
教授：7、7。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
0.
0。
4.
4。
PROFESSOR: The maximum of 0 and 4 plus 0, right?
教授：最大值为0和4加0，对吗？
AUDIENCE: 4.
听众：4。
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
7.
7。
PROFESSOR: So it's the maximum of 7 or 4 plus 0, so this is 7.
教授：这是7或4加0的最大值，所以是7。
AUDIENCE: 7.
听众：7。
11.
11。
PROFESSOR: 7 or 4 plus 7.
教授：7或4加7。
Does this make sense for everyone?
这对每个人有意义吗？
Last column.
最后一列。
Let's do it.
我们开始做吧。
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
Feels like 0.
感觉像0。
0 again.
再次为0。
Why not?
为什么不？
4.
4。
How much does this thing weigh?
这东西重多少？
AUDIENCE: 4.
听众：4。
AUDIENCE: 7.
听众：7。
10.
10。
PROFESSOR: Sorry for my handwriting.
教授：对不起，我的笔迹。
AUDIENCE: And it needs to be 11 because you
听众：它必须是11，因为您
said that'd be the answer.
说的就是答案。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So it's 11 because it's either this guy or 10 plus DP of 1, 1.
所以是11，因为是这个人或10加DP的1、1。
The first item weighs 4, so I need
第一件重4，所以我需要
to look one right and four up when adding.
在添加时看起来一右四。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
Please say yes.
请说是。
AUDIENCE: What's the [INAUDIBLE] again?
听众：[音频不清晰]又是什么？
I get how if you're looking horizontally,
如果您水平看，我知道
the top thing is the max.
最重要的是最大
It's saying DP of i plus 1 j.
就是说我的DP加1 j。
PROFESSOR: So this is looking horizontally,
教授：这是水平的，
and this means I did not take item i.
这意味着我没有服用项目i。
AUDIENCE: You didn't take item i,
听众：您没有带走项目i，
but if you are going to take item i, you add the value of i,
但是如果您要使用项目i，则将i的值相加，
and then you look back for DP of i plus 1,
然后回头看我加1的DP
which is the previous column, and the row number is whatever
这是前一列，行号是
capacity you have left if you did take it?
如果您接受了，您已经离开了吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: And so in the case of cell 1,
听众：因此，在单元格1的情况下
3, if you took item one, then capacity you'd have left is 3.
3，如果您选择了第一项，那么您剩下的容量为3。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
So you said total capacity three, right?
所以您说的总容量为三，对吗？
So if I take item one, how many pounds does it have?
因此，如果我服用第一个物品，它有多少磅？
AUDIENCE: It has four.
听众：有四个。
PROFESSOR: Statue is 0, ball is 1, pen is 2.
教授：雕像是0，球是1，笔是2。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
You're not using--
您没有使用-
PROFESSOR: So I'm using those items,
教授：所以我正在使用这些物品，
but I'm starting using zero based indexing.
但我开始使用基于零的索引。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, but we're going from here to here.
听众：是的，但是我们要从这里到这里。
So I'm saying if you pick the middle cell that's
所以我是说如果您选择中间的单元格
1, 3, that one--
一三三
PROFESSOR: So this has item one, so the ball, weight three.
教授：这是项目1，是球，重量是3。
If I take the ball, how much weight do I have left?
如果我接球，还剩下多少重量？
AUDIENCE: The ball weighs two pounds,
听众：球重两磅，
so you'd have three pounds left, and that's
所以你只剩三磅了
why you're in the three column.
为什么您在三列中。
PROFESSOR: I have a backpack of three pounds,
教授：我有一个三磅的背包，
and then I put a ball of two pounds in it,
然后我在里面放了两磅的球
and I have three pounds left?
还有三磅吗？
AUDIENCE: No, no, no.
听众：不，不，不。
You have three pounds left if you put a ball and two pounds
如果您放一个球，您还有三磅和两磅
in, right?
在吧？
PROFESSOR: I have a backpack of three pounds.
教授：我有一个三磅的背包。
I put a ball of two pounds.
我放了两磅的球。
How many pounds do I have left of capacity?
我还剩多少磅？
So backpack, three pounds total.
所以背包，总共三磅。
I put a ball in that has two pounds.
我把一个两磅的球放进去。
How many pounds?
多少磅？
AUDIENCE: We have none left.
听众：我们什么都没有了。
Oh, it can hold three total pounds?
哦，总共可以装三磅吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Then you have one pound left.
听众：那你还剩一磅。
But we have a five pound backpack.
但是我们有一个五磅的背包。
PROFESSOR: Well, you said we were looking at 3, 1.
教授：好，您说的是3，1。
You said we were looking here.
你说过我们在看这里
AUDIENCE: Yeah, we're looking there.
听众：是的，我们正在寻找。
PROFESSOR: So this means three pound backpack,
教授：这意味着三磅重的背包，
because the sub-problem says your weight is at most j.
因为该子问题说您的体重最多为j。
AUDIENCE: Got it, OK.
听众：知道了，好的。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
So j minus si is saying--
所以j减去si在说-
PROFESSOR: It means you used up, so you put up something there,
教授：这意味着您已经用光了，所以在这里放了东西，
so you ate some capacity.
所以你吃了一些容量。
AUDIENCE: Well, you ate only two pounds, though,
听众：嗯，虽然你只吃了两磅，
so why is it in row three?
那为什么在第三行呢？
PROFESSOR: You told me to start here.
教授：您叫我从这里开始。
AUDIENCE: I know.
听众：我知道。
I'm trying to remember how we got there.
我想记住我们是如何到达那里的。
PROFESSOR: You said, let's start here.
教授：您说的，让我们从这里开始。
That's why this arrow points here to one.
这就是为什么此箭头指向此处的原因。
You have two arrows, 2, 3, and 2, 1.
您有两个箭头2、3和2、1。
AUDIENCE: Because it's j minus si.
听众：因为是j减去si。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
Minus 3.
减3。
AUDIENCE: So j is the amount of weight you have left, right?
听众：那么j是您剩下的重量，对吗？
PROFESSOR: So j is the amount of weight
教授：所以j是重量
I can have for this sub-problem.
我可以解决这个子问题。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, the amount of capacity I
听众：是的，我的容量
have still in my backpack.
还在我的背包里。
PROFESSOR: Let's talk about pseudo polynomial time
教授：让我们谈谈伪多项式时间
very quickly and what does it mean, OK?
很快，这是什么意思，好吗？
And you guys will promise to look at the recitation notes
你们保证会看朗诵笔记
and look at the other problems, right?
看看其他问题吧？
So incentive for that.
因此激励。
Problem two is easier than knapsack,
问题二比背包容易，
so if you get that, that should be a good confirmation that you
因此，如果您知道了，那应该很好地证明您
got knapsack.
有背包。
Problem three is a bit harder than problem two,
问题三比问题二难，
but it shows up on interviews, so you
但它会显示在采访中
want to understand problem three.
想了解问题三。
I got problem two twice in four years,
四年来我两次遇到问题，
so there's a decent chance that you'll get it.
因此您很有可能得到它。
So you want to get to problem three,
所以你想解决问题三，
so you should go through problem two.
所以你应该经历第二个问题。
AUDIENCE: How many times have you got problem three?
听众：您有多少次遇到问题三了？
PROFESSOR: Twice in four years, so that's
教授：四年内两次，所以
the problem that you want to get to.
您想要解决的问题。
Problem two is a stepping stone.
问题二是垫脚石。
So running time for dynamic programming.
因此运行时间为动态编程。
How many sub-problems?
有多少个子问题？
AUDIENCE: Same, ns.
观众：ns。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Sub-problems.
子问题。
How many sub-problems do I look at when
我什么时候看多少个子问题
I compute the answer of a sub-problem?
我计算一个子问题的答案？
Two, right?
二对吧
So order one.
所以订购一个。
So this is how much time it takes
这是需要多少时间
to compute the answer to a sub-problem,
计算子问题的答案，
because I have the max of two elements,
因为我最多拥有两个元素，
so it's constant time.
所以这是恒定的时间。
So the total running time is?
那么总的运行时间是？
AUDIENCE: Order ns.
听众：命令ns。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Order of ns.
ns的顺序。
This polynomial, is this the same kind
这个多项式就是这种
of algorithm as Dijkstra?
Dijkstra的算法？
AUDIENCE: Pseudo polynomial.
听众：伪多项式。
PROFESSOR: Pseudo polynomial.
教授：伪多项式。
AUDIENCE: Don't know why.
听众：不知道为什么。
PROFESSOR: So intuitively, the problem
教授：从直觉上讲，这个问题
is s shows up in your running here,
在您的跑步中显示s时，
and s is the property of your input numbers.
s是输入数字的属性。
It's not how many elements you have in the input.
输入中没有多少元素。
It's what's inside one of those elements.
这些元素之一就是里面的东西。
So let's see why that matters.
那么，让我们看看为什么这很重要。
Let's look at the practical example.
让我们看一个实际的例子。
AUDIENCE: What about measuring in cubic inches
观众：以立方英寸为单位
or cubic centimeters?
或立方厘米？
Is that a problem?
那是问题吗？
It would take a lot longer if we do it in cubic centimeters.
如果以立方厘米为单位，则需要更长的时间。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but then you could
教授：是的，但是你可以
argue that if it's an integer amount of cubic inches,
认为如果是立方英寸的整数，
you should divide everything by that.
您应该将所有内容除以。
Where this really matters is suppose
假设这真的很重要
you have a 100 item input, so 100 items.
您输入了100个项目，因此输入了100个项目。
What's the worst case input on a 32-bit machine?
在32位计算机上最坏的情况是什么？
An input looks like this, by the way.
顺便说一句，输入看起来像这样。
How many elements you have, so 3, and then for each item,
您有多少个元素，因此为3，然后对于每个项目，
what's the weight and what's the value?
重量是多少，价值是什么？
So then we're going to have three weights, which I believe
因此，我们将拥有三个权重，我相信
are 4, 2, 3.
是4、2、3
You guys have to take my word for it.
你们必须相信我的话。
And then I have three values, which are 10, 4, 7.
然后我有三个值，分别是10、4、7。
Let's not worry about the values.
让我们不必担心这些值。
I claim that they're irrelevant.
我声称它们无关紧要。
You can convince yourselves afterwards
之后你可以说服自己
that that's the case.
就是这种情况。
Let's only look at this.
让我们只看这个。
The weights have to be between 0 and what for the problem
权重必须介于0和问题之间
to make sense?
有道理吗？
AUDIENCE: 5.
听众：5。
PROFESSOR: If I have a weight bigger than this,
教授：如果我的体重比这个大，
I know I'm not going to take that item.
我知道我不会拿那个东西。
How many bits do I need to represent these weights?
我需要多少位来表示这些权重？
AUDIENCE: Log s.
听众：登录。
PROFESSOR: It's log s plus 1 technically,
教授：从技术上来说，这是对数加1，
but if I write order of log s, I'm good.
但是如果我写log的顺序，那很好。
AUDIENCE: Times the number of items.
听众：乘以项目数。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
So if I want to represent all of them,
所以，如果我想代表所有人
I have order of n times log s, plus the number
我有n次log s的命令，加上数字
of bits required to represent this.
代表这一点的位数。
This is log n.
这是日志n。
So log n is smaller than n.
因此log n小于n。
I'm not going to add it here.
我不会在这里添加它。
So this is my input size.
这就是我的输入大小。
This is how many bits I need for the input.
这是我需要多少位输入。
So the worst case input on a 32-bit machine
因此，在32位计算机上输入的最坏情况
is going to have roughly 3,200 bits.
将有大约3200位。
What's the worst case s that I can
我能遇到的最坏情况是什么
represent on a 32-bit machine?
代表一台32位计算机？
These are all 32-bit numbers.
这些都是32位数字。
AUDIENCE: You mean each of the weights are 32-bit numbers?
听众：您是说每个权重都是32位数字？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So what's the worst case s I can represent?
那么我能代表的最坏情况是什么？
AUDIENCE: 2 to 31 minus 1.
受众群体：2到31减去1。
PROFESSOR: Which is roughly 4 times 10 to the ninth.
教授：大约是第九的10的4倍。
So the worst case running time is?
那么最坏的情况下运行时间是？
Roughly ns, right?
大约ns，对不对？
So n times s, which means roughly 100 times 10
所以n乘以s，大约等于100乘以10
to the ninth, which means 4 times 10 to the 11 operations.
到第九，这表示10到11运算的4倍。
Now, suppose we're looking at the worst case
现在，假设我们正在研究最坏的情况
input on a 64-bit machine.
在64位计算机上输入。
Still 100 items.
仍然有100个项目。
What's the input size?
输入大小是多少？
AUDIENCE: To the 21 total at the end.
听众：到最后共有21个。
PROFESSOR: That's how many operations.
教授：那是多少个手术。
Let's go through it step by step.
让我们逐步进行。
How many bits of input?
输入多少位？
AUDIENCE: 6,400.
观众：6,400。
AUDIENCE: Where does that come from?
听众：这是哪里来的？
AUDIENCE: 100 items times 32 bits.
观众：100项乘以32位。
PROFESSOR: 100 items.
教授：100件。
Each item weight has 64 bits.
每个项目权重都有64位。
What's the worst case s?
最糟糕的情况是什么？
AUDIENCE: 2 to the 64.
听众：2到64。
PROFESSOR: 2 to the 64 minus 1.
教授：2到64减1。
Doesn't matter too much.
没关系。
It's 1 times 10 to the 19th, 1.6 times 10 to the 19th.
是10到19的1倍，是10到19的1.6倍。
So the worst case running time is?
那么最坏的情况下运行时间是？
AUDIENCE: 10 to the 21.
听众：10到21。
PROFESSOR: 10 to the 21.
教授：10至21。
So what happened?
所以发生了什么事？
I increased my word size.
我增加了字数。
The running time increased quadratically.
运行时间增加了两倍。
This is not a polynomial increase.
这不是多项式的增加。
What's the problem here?
这是什么问题
Why is this the case?
为什么会这样呢？
If I write log s as b, so log s becomes
如果我将log s写为b，则log s变为
b, what's the input size?
b，输入大小是多少？
AUDIENCE: nb.
听众：nb。
PROFESSOR: Yep. n times log s equals n times b,
教授：是的。 n次log s等于n次b，
so this is the input size.
所以这是输入大小。
Now, what is the running time?
现在，运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: The number of operations?
听众：手术次数？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: n times 2 to the b.
听众：n乘以2到b。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
n times s, and s is 2 to the b.
n乘以s，而s是b的2。
So this is the problem.
所以这就是问题所在。
This is a polynomial in n and b, but here,
这是n和b中的多项式，但是在这里，
if I write the input this way, I have b as an exponent.
如果以这种方式编写输入，则我将b作为指数。
So if I double the number of bits
所以如果我把位数加倍
by doubling the field size, my running time
通过将字段大小加倍，我的运行时间
increases quadratically, so this is not polynomial.
平方增加，所以这不是多项式。
However, if I write it as order of n times s,
但是，如果我将其写为s的n倍，
this looks like a polynomial.
这看起来像多项式。
So it looks like a polynomial, but it's not truly
因此它看起来像多项式，但并不是真正的
a polynomial, so that's why it's pseudo, as in fake.
多项式，这就是为什么它是伪的，就像是假的。
AUDIENCE: So it's actually exponential.
听众：所以它实际上是指数的。
PROFESSOR: It's not exponential.
教授：不是指数的。
So an exponential algorithm for this means
所以这个的指数算法
try all the possible subsets, and that's
尝试所有可能的子集，那就是
order of 2 to the n times n to compute the sum.
2到n乘以n的阶来计算总和。
This is exponential, right?
这是指数的，对不对？
You have n here.
你在这里
It's clear.
很明显。
AUDIENCE: I know, but if you have 2 to the b,
听众：我知道，但是如果b等于2，
that seems pretty clear as well.
这似乎也很清楚。
PROFESSOR: Well, you have to look inside this s
教授：好吧，您必须仔细阅读
and see what it means.
并查看其含义。
That's the difference.
就是这样。
So by increasing the number of items,
因此，通过增加项目数量，
if you double the number of items
如果您将物品数量加倍
but you don't do anything to the word size,
但您不会对字号做任何事情，
then your running time is going to increase polynomially,
那么您的跑步时间将成倍增加，
but if you change the field size,
但是如果您更改字段大小，
it's going to increase exponentially.
它会成倍增加。
So pseudo polynomial means watch out, there's a trap.
因此，伪多项式意味着要当心，这是一个陷阱。
It's not really polynomial.
它不是真正的多项式。
If you increase the input size by increasing the number width,
如果您通过增加数字宽度来增加输入大小，
bad stuff is going to happen.
坏事将会发生。
So think of Dijkstra.
所以想想Dijkstra。
What's the running time of Dijkstra?
Dijkstra的运行时间是几点？
You count the number of vertices, the number of edges,
您计算顶点数，边数，
and you have a polynomial in that, right?
而且您有一个多项式，对吗？
You don't have to look at the number size.
您不必查看数字大小。
You don't have to look at any weird stuff like that.
您无需查看任何类似的怪异内容。
Here, you do.
在这里，你做。
That's the difference.
就是这样。
Does it make more sense?
它更有意义吗？
So whenever you have an input number that shows up
因此，只要您有显示的输入数字
in your running time, instead of how many numbers you have,
在您的跑步时间内，而不是您拥有多少个数字，
that means there's a trap.
那意味着有一个陷阱。
That's pseudo polynomial.
那是伪多项式。
AUDIENCE: So it's just like having some constant
听众：就像保持不变
that depends on something?
取决于什么？
PROFESSOR: It's not a constant.
教授：这不是一个常数。
AUDIENCE: I mean coefficient.
听众：我的意思是系数。
AUDIENCE: Once you set it, it's a constant, right?
听众：设置好之后，它是一个常数，对吗？
PROFESSOR: I mean, that's true for everything, right?
教授：我的意思是，所有事情都是这样，对吗？
You can say that you have 10 to the 80 atoms in the universe,
您可以说宇宙中有10到80个原子，
so all the numbers that you work with are at most 10 to the 80.
因此您使用的所有数字最多为10到80。
Therefore, your running time is order one
因此，您的跑步时间是一阶
no matter what you do, and then running times
不管你做什么，然后运行时间
are no longer useful.
不再有用。
You have to draw a line somewhere.
您必须在某处画一条线。
AUDIENCE: I think it's just like s, if it depends on your field
听众：我想就像s一样，取决于您的领域
size and you can scale it, it's kind of like--
大小，您可以缩放它，有点像-
PROFESSOR: So asymptotic running time.
教授：渐近的运行时间。
What's the point of that?
有什么意义呢？
How do our algorithms scale?
我们的算法如何扩展？
As our data becomes bigger and bigger,
随着我们的数据越来越大，
what happens to the running time?
运行时间会怎样？
This pseudo polynomial thing tells you
这个伪多项式告诉你
that if you're shifting to a larger number size,
如果您要转换为更大的数字，
to a larger word size, then your running time
较大的单词，然后是您的运行时间
is going to explode.
会爆炸。
It's not going to scale linearly.
它不会线性扩展。
Still don't buy it?
还是不买吗？
AUDIENCE: I trust you, I just--
听众：我相信你，我只是-
AUDIENCE: So it's only dependent on the field in this case.
听众：在这种情况下，它仅取决于字段。
PROFESSOR: Do you guys want to look over Dijkstra
教授：你们想看看Dijkstra吗
and see what the input to Dijkstra looks like
看看Dijkstra的输入是什么样子
and why that's different?
为什么不同呢？
Do you think that's worth your time,
您认为这值得您度过吗，
given that this is what's standing
鉴于这就是现状
between you and the weekend?
你和周末之间？
AUDIENCE: What time is it?
听众：现在几点了？
PROFESSOR: If you guys want to, I'm willing to do it.
教授：如果你们愿意，我愿意这样做。
AUDIENCE: It's 4:07.
听众：4:07。
I'll stay.
我会留下来。
PROFESSOR: Well, if you guys want to go, you can go.
教授：好吧，如果你们想走，那就可以走。
I will draw this for the people who
我会为那些
still want to know what it looks like.
仍然想知道它是什么样子。
Dijkstra.
迪克斯特拉。
What's the input to Dijkstra?
Dijkstra的输入是什么？
It's a graph, right?
是图，对不对？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, nodes and edges.
听众：是的，节点和边缘。
PROFESSOR: What does the graph look like?
教授：图形是什么样的？
It's some number of nodes, so it's
它是一些节点，所以
a single number-- that's the number of nodes--
一个数字-即节点数-
that has log v bits in it.
其中有log v位。
And then for each edge, we have three numbers-- first vertex,
然后对于每个边，我们有三个数字-第一个顶点
second vertex, and the weight.
第二个顶点和权重。
What are the sizes of these numbers?
这些数字的大小是多少？
Log v, log v, and the last one?
Log v，log v和最后一个？
AUDIENCE: Log w?
听众：登录w？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And what's w?
那是什么？
AUDIENCE: Maximum weight.
听众：最大重量。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So this is a property of the field size, right?
这是字段大小的属性，对吗？
Let's look at v, actually.
让我们看一下v。
So we have E edges here, right?
所以我们这里有E条边，对不对？
So the input size is going to be log v bits plus E times log v
所以输入大小将是log v位加上E乘log v
plus log w.
加日志w。
AUDIENCE: How did you get that?
听众：你是怎么得到的？
PROFESSOR: Because I have the edges, so I have E of these.
教授：因为我有边，所以我有这些。
I only have one vertex count, but then I have E edges,
我只有一个顶点数，但是我有E个边，
and each edge has three numbers, and these
每个边都有三个数字，这些
are the widths of the numbers.
是数字的宽度。
AUDIENCE: Is the adjacent edges to v?
听众：v的相邻边是吗？
Is that right?
那正确吗？
You say you have E edges.
您说您有E条边。
PROFESSOR: I'm assuming it's a list,
教授：我假设是清单，
so the most compact representation
所以最紧凑的表示
of edges, I think-- or it might be a reasonably
我认为-或可能是合理的
compact representation is that you have the list of edges.
紧凑的表示法是您具有边列表。
So you have a graph that has five nodes,
因此，您有一个包含五个节点的图，
and then you have an edge that goes from 1 to 2,
然后您具有从1到2的边
and then weight 3, an edge that goes from 1 to 5, weight 4.
然后权重3，即从1到5的边，权重4。
AUDIENCE: If you use a number, it's not a--
听众：如果您使用数字，那不是-
PROFESSOR: Well, do I need anything else for vertices?
教授：那么，我还需要顶点吗？
Not really, right?
不是真的吧？
AUDIENCE: So v1 and v2 are neighbors of capital V?
听众：那么v1和v2是大写V的邻居吗？
PROFESSOR: So v1, v2, w, these are the first edge.
教授：因此，v1，v2，w是第一个优势。
Each edge has these fields.
每个边都有这些字段。
AUDIENCE: This is the entire graph in one thing.
听众：这是一整个图。
PROFESSOR: This is the entire graph as a list of numbers,
教授：这是整个图形，是一个数字列表，
and this is how many bits it takes
这是需要多少位
to represent the graph in a reasonably
以合理的方式表示图形
compact representation.
紧凑的表示形式。
Now let's say little v is log v, little w is log w.
现在假设小v是对数v，小w是对数w。
So then this is order of how many bits do I have here?
那么，这是我在这里有多少位的顺序？
E times v plus w plus v. I just replaced the logs
E次v加w加v。我只是替换了日志
with these variables.
这些变量。
This is how many bits.
这是多少位。
Now, how many operations does Dijkstra take?
现在，Dijkstra需要进行多少次手术？
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: Well, it depends on--
听众：嗯，这取决于-
AUDIENCE: E log v.
观众：电子日志v。
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it be E plus v?
听众：不是E加v吗？
That's the fastest one, right?
那是最快的吧？
But I think practically, it's only going to be--
但实际上，我认为这只会是-
PROFESSOR: So this is E plus v log
教授：这就是E加v的对数
v, the fastest theoretical limit.
v，最快的理论极限。
This is still smaller than E log v. This
这仍然小于E log v。
is going to make my life easier.
将使我的生活更轻松。
So this is smaller than this.
所以这比这个小。
If this thing is polynomial, this is polynomial for sure.
如果这个东西是多项式，那肯定是多项式。
E log v is E times little v. So how many bits in the input?
E log v是E乘以小v。那么输入中有多少位？
E times v plus w.
E乘以v加w。
How many operations?
多少次手术？
E times v. Any exponential anywhere here?
E时代v。这里任何地方都有指数吗？
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't you change the size of v?
听众：您不会更改v的大小吗？
That looks fine.
看起来不错。
PROFESSOR: Well, so there is a trick that v is 2 to the v,
教授：好吧，有个窍门是v等于v，2
right?
对？
So you can say that this is order
所以你可以说这是命令
of-- so this is definitely bigger than 2
-绝对大于2
to the little v times v, but then you
到小v乘v，但是然后你
have the same thing in the input.
在输入中有相同的内容。
So the input also has at least 2 to the little v times v bits.
因此，输入也至少具有2到小的v乘以v位。
But don't worry about that.
但是不用担心。
That's too much.
这太多了。
The point is if you're worrying about this, don't worry.
关键是，如果您为此担心，请不要担心。
The math still works out.
数学仍然可行。
So whatever you have here as an input,
所以无论您有什么输入
the running time is going to be a polynomial
运行时间将是一个多项式
in the size of the input.
输入的大小。
What happens if you double the word size?
如果单词大小加倍会怎样？
What happens if you have bigger weights?
如果您的体重更大，会怎样？
AUDIENCE: Everything like v is multiplied by 2,
听众：v之类的东西都乘以2，
and w is multiplied by 2 and everything in this problem,
w被2乘以这个问题的一切，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: So if you're doubling the word size,
教授：所以，如果您将字号加倍，
then this is going to double, this is going to double.
然后这将增加一倍，这将增加一倍。
Everything's fine.
一切安好。
What if you double the size of the weights?
如果将砝码的大小加倍怎么办？
AUDIENCE: That only adds an extra bit.
听众：这只会增加一点点。
PROFESSOR: Sorry.
教授：对不起。
So if you double the size of the weight numbers?
那么，如果您将重量数字的大小加倍？
So if you move from 32-bit weights to 64-bit weights?
那么，如果您从32位权重转移到64位权重？
AUDIENCE: That's still a constant factor, right?
听众：这仍然是一个不变的因素，对吗？
PROFESSOR: What happens to the running time?
教授：运行时间会怎样？
AUDIENCE: Nothing.
听众：没事。
PROFESSOR: Nothing.
教授：没事。
w does not show up in Dijkstra.
w没有出现在Dijkstra中。
If it would, then we'd be trouble.
如果可以的话，那就麻烦了。
It wouldn't be polynomial anymore.
它不再是多项式了。
AUDIENCE: But practically, you will
听众：但是实际上，您会
be accessing that number, right?
正在访问该号码，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but that shows up
教授：是的，但是那显示出来了
in the cost of one operation.
一次手术的成本。
That's why I'm saying this is how many operations
这就是为什么我说这是多少操作
you do, how many arithmetic operations.
你要做多少算术运算。
Then the model of computation that we use is RAM,
那么我们使用的计算模型是RAM
and that says that you can do any math
那说你可以做任何数学
operation in order one.
操作顺序一。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So here, my number in the input,
教授：所以这里，我输入的数字，
s, which is the size of a weight,
s，即重量的大小，
showed up in the running time.
出现在运行时间。
AUDIENCE: Oh, the size of the input
听众：哦，输入的大小
showed up in the running time.
出现在运行时间。
PROFESSOR: So the size of the input is OK,
教授：所以输入的大小还可以，
but one number in the input showed up,
但输入中出现一个数字，
whereas here, that's not the case.
而在这里并非如此。
The weights do not show up in the running time.
砝码不会在运行时间中显示。
AUDIENCE: So why don't we just always run Dijkstra, then?
听众：那么，为什么我们不总是运行迪杰斯特拉呢？
PROFESSOR: Actually for this problem, for the knapsack
教授：实际上，对于这个问题，对于背包
problem, you can't find an algorithm that is polynomial.
问题，您无法找到多项式算法。
If you do, there's a $1 million prize for it
如果这样做，您将获得一百万美元的奖金
because you just proved that p equals mp.
因为您刚刚证明p等于mp。
This is the best we can do for knapsack.
这是我们能为背包做的最好的事情。
AUDIENCE: Is counting sort pseudo linear,
听众：正在计数排序伪线性，
because you need to have a maximum, a range?
因为需要最大范围？
Does that make sense?
那有意义吗？
PROFESSOR: Counting sort.
教授：计数排序。
AUDIENCE: Depends on your range.
听众：取决于您的范围。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but the range shows up under a log.
教授：是的，但范围显示在日志下方。
You're allowed to have logs.
您可以拥有日志。
You're allowed to have log w.
您可以拥有日志w。
You're not allowed to have w.
你不允许有w。
It's dependent on the size of the input.
这取决于输入的大小。
If you double the number size, then you're
如果将数字大小加倍，那么
going to have twice as many rounds,
将有两倍的回合，
but you don't have an exponential number of rounds.
但您没有指数级的回合。
Sorry.
抱歉。
You're thinking of counting sort.
您正在考虑计数排序。
I thought radix sort.
我以为基数排序。
Radix sort doesn't matter because you
基数排序并不重要，因为您
assume we can do everything in-- never mind.
假设我们可以做所有事情-没关系。
You're right for counting sort.
您是正确的排序排序。
Sorry.
抱歉。
You're right for counting sort.
您是正确的排序排序。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I was confusing counting sort with radix sort.
我把计数排序与基数排序混淆了。
So for counting sort, yeah, it's not linear.
因此，对于计数排序，是的，它不是线性的。
It's linear in your range size, which
它的范围大小是线性的
is not linear in the input size, which
输入大小不是线性的
is why we don't do counting sort.
这就是为什么我们不进行计数排序的原因。
We do radix sort.
我们做基数排序。
AUDIENCE: We do counting sort in radix sort?
观众：我们是在以基数排序计数吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But radix sort limits the size of the range, right?
但是基数排序限制了范围的大小，对吗？
That's the point of radix sort.
这就是基数排序的要点。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
I see what you're thinking.
我明白你在想什么。
So doing counting sort with each number?
那么对每个数字进行计数排序呢？
AUDIENCE: Right, with really big numbers,
听众：对，有很多数字，
taking a really long time.
花了很长时间。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, that would take a long time.
听众：是的，这将花费很长时间。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
That is very true.
是的。
If you try to do pure counting sort on 64-bit numbers,
如果您尝试对64位数字进行纯计数排序，
you're going to run out of RAM.
您将用完RAM。
Does this make some sense?
这有意义吗？
OK.
好。
Promise to look over the other problems, and in return,
承诺要解决其他问题，作为回报，
given that I didn't have time to cover them here,
鉴于我没有时间在这里报道它们，
I promise to answer any emails you
我保证会回复您的任何电子邮件
guys might ask me over the weekend.
周末可能会问我。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Awesome.
太棒了